

Teejay Hidalgo Web Developer (7 years)

teejay.hidalgo@gmail.com | https://teejayhidalgo.github.io

Profile and Objective

A professional back-end developer with 7-year full time experience as a back-end developer. Proficient knowledge of the back-end programming language/framework such as php, mysql, codeigniter. A good understanding of front-end web technologies likes HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Works well with front-end developers. Able to manage a hosting environment, including database administration as well as scaling applications to handle load changes. With experience in version control, such as Git. Looking for opportunities where I can continue to grow and learn as a web developer.

Experience

Jul 2011 - May 2017 (5 years 11 months)

Senior Web Developer

Sevenworks Inc. | National Capital Reg, Philippines

Industry Computer / Information Technology (Software)

Specialization IT/Computer - Software Role Backend Web Developer

Position Level Senior

- Writing, maintaining and enhancing program code
- Creating, maintaining, and enhancing databases
- Testing, debugging, diagnosing and correcting errors and bugs in an application
- Leading a team to ensure that the project specification is met and is delivered in a timely manner
- Reviewing current system, process and presenting improvements and solutions
- · Researching and integration of APIs, plugins and extensions
- Preparing documentations
- Working closely with designers, customer support and QA in the development process
- Working closely with product managers and business partners to understand the software requirements

Nov 2009 - Apr 2011 (1 year 6 months)

Junior Web Developer

Invertise Multimedia Design Corporation | National Capital Reg, Philippines

Industry Computer / Information Technology (Software)

Specialization IT/Computer - Software
Role Backend Web Developer
Position Level Fresh / Entry Level

- Setup and configure the CMS and database for new projects
- · Writing new codes for projects requiring new functions and enhancements

- Analysis of client requirement and propose solutions and enhancements
- · Maintaining, enhancing website and database
- Testing, debugging and troubleshooting websites
- Contributing in the development of an internal CMS framework for the company

Education

2005 - 2009 De La Salle University Manila

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science/Information Technology | Philippines

Key Skills

Advanced PHP, MySQL, Codeigniter

Intermediate Javascript, Jquery, HTML, CSS, Git, Github

Basic Java, Laravel, NodeJs, MS Access, Magento, Cpanel, Wordpress, Joomla,

Prestashop

Personal Skills

Understanding new concepts and applying them correctly.

- Ability to look from business perspective apart from code-level perspective.
- Logical, understands a problem to the very bottom.
- Works with minimal supervision.
- · Resourceful and great at researching.

Languages

Proficiency level: 0 - Poor, 10 - Excellent

Language	Spoken	Written
Filipino (Primary)	9	9
English	7	9
Japanese	2	2

About Me

Gender Male
Age 31 years
Status Single

Address Adachi Ku Sekibara, Tokyo, Japan

Nationality Philippines Status Single